Mike Schaekermann

49 Columbia St W, Unit 101 Waterloo, ON N2L 3K4 mschaeke@uwaterloo.ca +1 (647) 573-2908

https://cs.uwaterloo.ca/~mschaeke/

OVERVIEW

My research focuses on developing methods to capture and utilize the structure of ambiguous classification problems in the context of human-centered machine learning and human-AI collaboration. My work has a special focus on medical data analysis.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science	2016 - 2020 (expected)
University of Waterloo, ON, Canada	
Advisors: Edith Law and Kate Larson	

Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Media Informatics	2014
Salzburg University of Applied Sciences, Austria	
Thesis Supervisor: Lennart Nacke	

Staatsexamen (equivalent to Bachelors), Medicine	2011
University of Marburg, Germany	

AWARDS & HONOURS

G	
Google PhD Fellowship (\$45,000/year)	2018-2020
Best Paper, ACM CSCW	2018
Graduate Excellence Scholarship (\$5,000) — UWaterloo	2017
David R. Cheriton Graduate Scholarship (\$10,000) — UWaterloo	2016
International Doctoral Student Award (\$11,760/year) — UWaterloo	2016
Amazon Web Services Research Grant (\$7,000) — Amazon	2016
Merit-based Scholarship — Salzburg University of Applied Sciences	2014
Merit-based Scholarship for Foreign Studies	2014
Engineering Scholarship — both Economic Chamber of Salzburg	2013
Nominee for the German National Academic Foundation	2009

CONFERENCE PAPERS

Trusted AI and the Contribution of Trust Modeling in Multiagent Systems. Cohen, R., Schaekermann, M., Liu, S., & Cormier, M. AAMAS'19. Montréal.

Resolvable vs. Irresolvable Disagreement: A Study on Worker Deliberation in Crowd Work. Schaekermann, M., Goh, J., Larson, K., & Law, E. CSCW'18. New York City, NY. [Best Paper Award]

Curiously Motivated: Profiling Curiosity with Self-Reports and Behaviour Metrics in the Game Destiny. Schaekermann, M., Ribeiro, G., Wallner, G., Kriglstein, S., Johnson, D., Drachen, A., & Nacke, L. E. CHI PLAY'17. Amsterdam, Netherlands.

Online Bayesian Transfer Learning for Sequential Data Modeling. Jaini, P., Chen, Z., Carbajal, P., Law, E., Middleton, L., Regan, K., Schaekermann, M., Trimponias, G., Tung, J., & Poupart, P. ICLR'17. Toulon, France.

Testing Incremental Difficulty Design in Platformer Games. Wehbe, R. R., Mekler, E. D., Schaekermann, M., Lank, E., & Nacke, L. E. CHI'17. Denver, CO.

WORKSHOP PAPERS & ABSTRACTS

crowdEEG: A Platform for Structured Consensus Formation in Medical Time Series Analysis. Schaekermann, M., Beaton, G., Habib, M., Lim, A., Larson, K., & Law, E. 8th Workshop on Interactive Systems in Healthcare (WISH) at CHI'19. Glasgow, UK.

Capturing Expert Arguments from Medical Adjudication Discussions in a Machine-readable Format. Schaekermann, M., Beaton, G., Habib, M., Lim, A., Larson, K., & Law, E. 2nd Workshop on Subjectivity, Ambiguity and Disagreement (SAD) in Crowdsourcing at WebConf'19. San Francisco, CA.

Utilizing a wearable smartphone-based EEG for pediatric epilepsy patients in the resource poor environment of Guinea: A prospective study. Williams, J., Cisse, F.A., Schaekermann, M., Sakadi, F., Tassiou, N.R., Bah, A.K., Hamani, A.B.D., Lim, A., Leung, E.C.W., Fantaneau, T.A., Milligan, T., Khatri, V., Hoch, D., Vyas, M., Lam, A., Hotan, G., Cohen, J., Law, E., & Mateen, F. Annual Meeting of the American Academy of Neurology **AAN'19**. Philadelphia, PA.

Expert Disagreement in Sequential Labeling: A Case Study on Adjudication in Medical Time Series Analysis. Schaekermann, M., Lim, A., Larson, K., & Law, E. 1st Workshop on Subjectivity, Ambiguity and Disagreement (SAD) in Crowdsourcing at HCOMP'18. Zurich, Switzerland.

Resolvable vs. Irresolvable Ambiguity: A New Hybrid Framework for Dealing with Uncertain Ground Truth. Schaekermann, M., Law, E., Williams, A. C., & Callaghan, W. Workshop on Human-Centered Machine Learning at CHI'16. San Jose, CA.

CONFERENCE WORKSHOPS

Subjectivity, Ambiguity and Disagreement in Crowdsourcing. Co-chaired with Chris Welty, Lora Aroyo, Praveen Paritosh, Anca Dumitrache, Jennimaria Palomaki, Alex Quinn, Olivia Rheinhart, & Michael Tseng at WebConf'19.

Designing for Curiosity: an Interdisciplinary Workshop. Co-organized with Edith Law, Pierre-Yves Oudeyer, Ming Yin, & Alex Williams at CHI'17.

RESEARCH &
WORK
EXPERIENCE

Student Researcher, Google Brain, Mountain View, CA	2018 - present
Research Intern, Google Brain, Mountain View, CA	2018

Visiting Researcher, Inria Bordeaux, France 2017

Software Engineering Intern, Google, Mountain View, CA 2017

Entrepreneur, SpontaneousOrder GmbH, Berlin, Germany 2011 - 2015

Visiting Researcher, Ontario Tech University, ON, Canada 2013 - 2014

Research Assistant, University Medical Center, Marburg, Germany 2009 - 2010

SELECTED PROJECTS

crowdEEG.ca

Framework to combine machine and human intelligence for the scalable and accurate analysis of human clinical EEG recordings. This is an active research project in the HCI CrowdLab at the University of Waterloo, Canada, led by professor Edith Law.

3D Simulation of the Human Endocrine System

Real-time 3D simulation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis, a part of the human neuro-endocrine system. Final project for "Simulation Methods in Physiology and Neurobiology" at medical school of University of Marburg, Germany.

SERVICE & LEADERSHIP

Journal Reviewer: ACM Transactions on Interactive Intelligent Systems (2017) Conference Reviewer: CHI (2017, 2018, 2019), CSCW (2018), CHI PLAY (2016)

Program Committee: CrowdBias 2018, HumBL 2019

Other: Advisor for incoming international students (2012), and president of the students council (2013) at Salzburg University of Applied Sciences, Austria